

Charles Chuka Osegbue

Lagos State, Nigeria. +2348103442322, +2347019227318

osegbuecharles.com - osegbuecharles@gmail.com

Professional Sumary

OSEGBUE CHARLES

Well trained Computer Scientist with mid to high level experience in information technology. Areas of expertise include web design, software development, IT personnel and computer maintenance. Enthusiastic programmer well versed in a range of e-solutions and technologies.

Education

○ BACHELOR OF SCIENCE(COMPUTER SCIENCE)

2016 - 2020

Augustine University Ilara Epe, Lagos, Nigeria

- First Class Honors
- Best Graduating Student Faculty of Science 2020
- Pioneer President Faculty of Science Student Association (FACUSSA),
 2019/2020 Academic Session
- Deans list Student for 3 years in a row
- Project Work: Clinic Management System

HIGH SCHOOL CERTIFICATE

2010 - 2016

St. Vincent Catholic School Bammeke ShaSha, Lagos, Nigeria

- Senior Prefect (Head Boy)
- Set Valecdictorian
- CowbellPedia Maths Competition
- Milo Basketball Competition
- St. Agnes Fine arts competition

Professional Experience

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

2022 - Present

Freelance, Remote

- Build and manage custom websites for companies/organizations.
- Optimize Websites using best SEO practices.
- Web Development Consultation.

FACULTY HEAD

2021 - 2022

Complete Computers and Technology, Benin, Nigeria

- Head of the Python Faculty
- Taught python as a certification course to aspiring developers.
- Taught Corporate Microsoft Office as a certification course.

SENIOR DEVELOPER

2019 - 2021

Wine Red 🖁 , Lagos, Nigeria

→ JUNIOR DEVELOPER (INTERN)

April,2018 - Oct,2018

Fountain of Love Systems, GM PLAZA, Lagos, Nigeria

- Testing and Debugging of projects made by senior developers
- Setting Milestone Progress for Projects
- Creating User Manual on Softwares for Clients
- Presenting and explaining Software functionality to clients
- Building Python Based Applications for Sensitive Projects

IT SUPPORT PERSONNEL (INTERN)

August,2017 - Oct,2017, August,2018 - Oct,2018

CCOTTECH, Lagos, Nigeria

- Assisting Senior It Personnel in monitoring servers
- Answering phone calls for the It department
- Assisting Senior It Personnel in Server Installation and relocation
- Clipping cat 6 cables
- Assisting Senior It Personnel in installing new thin clients for staffs

- Lead in Custom Website Development
- Delegate tasks to the 4 members of the development team and provide counsel on all aspects of the project.
- Supervise the assessment of all graphic materials in order to ensure quality and accuracy of the design
- Oversee the efficient use of production project budgets.

Maintenance and repair of thin clients, desktops and printers

Skills

- φ,
 - Adaptive Worker
 - Computer literate
 - Research and Analysis
 - Analytical Skill

Professional Skills

- Node JS

React

MongoDB

• Fast Learner

Web Design

• Team Player

Critical Thinking

Good Communication Skills

- FIGMA
- HTML 5
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Angular
- Type Script

- Redux
- Express
- MY SQL
- Adobe XD
- PHI
- Bootstrap
- Python
- Java
- C++

Projects

- 1. Baymar Eyecare(October,2020) an eye clinic website and admin portal, baymareyecare.com
- 2. ideal hr(January,2021) a human resource company website and admin portal, hrideal.com
- 3. Zane Models(August, 2021) a modelling agency website and admin portal, zanemodels.com
- 4. The Grind Roof Top(October,2021) a night club website and admin portal, grindrooftop.com
- 5. Link Click(March, 2022) a link shortener/monitoring website, c-l.link
- 6. CV Builder(April, 2022) a cv builder website, c-l.link/cvbuilder

Referees

Dr. Grace Oletu

Assistant Professor in Software Engineering, School of Information Technology & Computing, at American University of Nigeria,

Yola

+2349051651274

graceoletu@gmail.com

Dr. Ayodele Lasisi

Senior Lecturer Computer Science, at Augustine University Ilara Epe.

Dr. Raphael Ikechukwu Izuora

Corporate Services Manager at Nigeria Communications Commission,

Abuja

+2348157777909

eyekingdazle@gmail.com

Mr. Adeagbo Tolulope

Senior Developer Fountain of Love Systems Sangotedo, Lagos

+2347034247018 tolusoft2010@yahoo.com

A copy of this resume can be found at osegbuecharles.com/cv